[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f5", "question": "What US state's civil law is most closely based on the Napoleonic Code?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cadb", "question": "The \"canebrake\", \"timber\" and \"pygmy\" are types of what?", "answer": "Rattlesnakes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febaae27e83c707845b20e3", "question": "Hydrargyrum was once the name for what element?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eb0108d98002fdd633aa", "question": "What are the two cities in Charles Dickens' novel \"A Tale of Two Cities\"?", "answer": "London and Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a799", "question": "Opened in 1928, the original Gorky Park is an amusement park located in what world capital city?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398dc", "question": "What was the name of the Cartwright's ranch on the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Ponderosa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9df", "question": "Which branch of science is concerned with the study of matter and energy?", "answer": "Physics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddd1c6ce05a3942286da0", "question": "Heisenberg is the nickname of the main character in which popular television series?", "answer": "Breaking Bad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10d", "question": "Wiccaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Witches and witchcraft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a95d", "question": "What is Hungary's capital?", "answer": "Budapest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd42", "question": "What hall of Famer played his entire major-league career for the Minnesota Twins?", "answer": "Kirby Puckett", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008dcacf4f3bc4a292f861b", "question": "How many times was Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. arrested?", "answer": "29 (Many of the charges against him were illegitimate and the result of widespread, systemic racism.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f1", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600244634be4723ccac221a2", "question": "What is the movement in architecture in which buildings have an organic, amoeba-shaped form?", "answer": "Blobism\u00a0or\u00a0blobitecture\u00a0is a type of wavy, curvy building design without traditional edges or traditional symmetric form.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9093b01dd7bf43be5e88c", "question": "Which planet has the largest ocean in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b76", "question": "What movie director/producer owns Skywalker Ranch, in Marin County, California?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6af", "question": "What do climbers rub on their hands for extra grip?", "answer": "Chalk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf94", "question": "What does an onychophagist do?", "answer": "Bite their nails", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f5", "question": "How many possible first moves are there in chess?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339790", "question": "What is the name of the mansion where Elvis Presley died?", "answer": "Graceland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a980561d1b4d384d5d68b", "question": "Boise is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899dd160d398dc9cf7a6af", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d77", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Children's Crusade\"?", "answer": "Slaughterhouse-Five", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1e", "question": "What popular one-named musician's last name is Armstrong?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37a4815febcc896f9272", "question": "What Turkish city has spread to both sides of the Bosphorus Strait?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab69", "question": "Which major Australia city does the Fremantle city port serve?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339169", "question": "Who is The Friendly Ghost?", "answer": "Casper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdf", "question": "In the year 1900, what killed over 8,000 people in Galveston, Texas?", "answer": "Hurricane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c558", "question": "What is the common name for \"graphospasm\"?", "answer": "Writer's cramp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfdffbdb668d7dfe168b5bb", "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into noble metals was called what?", "answer": "Alchemy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94cf395ea27d7a1303aece", "question": "Which rapper went platinum with his 2014 Album \"2014 Forest Hills Drive\"?", "answer": "J. Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e08", "question": "What Shakespeare play begins with a meeting of the Weird Sisters?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb50365ff7d326b622a8c", "question": "Which play is believed to be Shakespeare's first tragedy?", "answer": "Titus Andronicus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ed", "question": "What TV series, which debuted in 1965, was set in the year 1997?", "answer": "Lost in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f72", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the strongest man on Earth?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a048", "question": "In what year was the hit game \"Minecraft\" released?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339237", "question": "What novel did Universal Studios pay Michael Crichton $2 million for before it was even published?", "answer": "Jurassic Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdfef3b668d7dfe168b5b2", "question": "In 1979 what did President Carter apologise to Australia about?", "answer": "Skylab falling on their country", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69daa20565ad31a57c779", "question": "What was the longest-ruling Chinese dynasty?", "answer": "Zhou", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96f2d23c87fd04dd15e40", "question": "What year did the Times Square Ball Drop first take place?", "answer": "1907, welcoming 1908", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7e65ff048f679a45ac0d", "question": "Barophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab11", "question": "Which sea lies east of mainland Greece?", "answer": "Aegean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df9", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Hermes?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c495", "question": "What vitamin group is mostly required for blood coagulation?", "answer": "Vitamin K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c532", "question": "What two dogs are bred to make a puggle?", "answer": "Pug and beagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e184fcbed638185eaa1b", "question": "What three countries intersect at Mount Roraima?", "answer": "Venezuela, Brazil, and Guyana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be07", "question": "Frank Sinatra was buried with a bottle of what whiskey?", "answer": "Jack Daniel's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe766e3eec85e375820b28b", "question": "You can find Grand Teton National Park in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26d", "question": "What is a nanominute?", "answer": "One-billionth of a minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c149", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning or knowledge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab83", "question": "What year did Sierra Leone gain its independence from the UK?", "answer": "1961", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d1", "question": "What word is used to describe the employees' side of a casino table?", "answer": "Pit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2e", "question": "Paper and Mud Dauber are types of what?", "answer": "Wasp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3d", "question": "In what platinum single by Marvin Gaye does he say he's hot just like an oven and needs some lovin'?", "answer": "Sexual Healing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd8", "question": "In Arthurian legend, what was the name of King Arthur's magic sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83f", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the loops of Henle?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31b", "question": "Which towering professional wrestler passed away on January 27, 1993?", "answer": "Andre the Giant", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42c", "question": "The Himalayas are located on which continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdab8480b8cce1e6fda7051", "question": "What is a Spanish canvas sandal decorated with rope called?", "answer": "Espadrille", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb03", "question": "What magazine publisher founded a motorcycle club called the \"Capitalist Tools\"?", "answer": "Malcolm Forbes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b042", "question": "What English king was known as the \"Lionheart\"?", "answer": "Richard (I)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b809", "question": "Who are the Mario Brothers usually trying to save?", "answer": "Princess Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11e", "question": "What famous animal character called \"Skull Island\" home?", "answer": "King Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc6", "question": "In literature, Dr. Abraham Van Helsing hunted what horror character?", "answer": "Dracula", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd4", "question": "According to legend, what was the name of the Roman slave who removed a thorn from the lion's foot?", "answer": "Androcles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d9", "question": "In The Simpsons, what does the old Radioactive Man #1 comic smell like according to Milhouse?", "answer": "His grandfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad58", "question": "Frank Wathernam was the last inmate to leave what infamous prison?", "answer": "Alcatraz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339768", "question": "What is written on the globe in Scarface's closing scene?", "answer": "The World Is Yours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a6d690aac110e4167081", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a669", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Land of Enchantment\"?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf8", "question": "Who was the first Russian woman to win a Wimbledon singles title?", "answer": "Maria Sharapova", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ad", "question": "What was the name of Bill Clinton's secretary who became popular during the Monica Lewinsky scandal?", "answer": "Betty Currie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff510ead24dd593ee3eacc8", "question": "Who was the first Republican Vice President of the United States?", "answer": "Hannibal Hamlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b536", "question": "What does an archer carry his arrows in?", "answer": "A Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1fb877e98cb97778982", "question": "In which US state will you find the world's largest rocking chair and world's largest mailbox?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c466", "question": "Which bodily organ produces urine?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae1", "question": "Hamlet was the Prince of which country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eb123f83302ff91e464a4", "question": "What brand of stapler is Milton Waddams attached to in the film \"Office Space\"?", "answer": "Swingline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9a", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Sawyer?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8fefa01dd7bf43be5e85f", "question": "Ablutophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Cleaning, bathing or washing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a290", "question": "What name did Cat Stevens adopt in 1977?", "answer": "Yusuf Islam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb65835dad637d903c8834", "question": "Where can you find the Petronas Towers?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a855", "question": "\"Lost City of the Incas\" is another name for what Peruvian site?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ec1406d333868d34d760", "question": "The name \"Australia\" was formally adopted in which year?", "answer": "1824", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb68cb5dad637d903c8844", "question": "The unofficial Wei\u00dfwurst\u00e4quator, or \"white sausage equator\", separates Bavaria and the south from the rest of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8d", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ac", "question": "How many watts make a kilowatt?", "answer": "1000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b6", "question": "What year was McDonalds' Big Mac sandwich first introduced?", "answer": "1967", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a033", "question": "In \"Family Guy\", what does Peter put in Joe's water making him win the Special People's games?", "answer": "Steroids", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beba", "question": "What Thames River town lent its name to the collarless polo shirts first worn by its rowing team?", "answer": "Henley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c687", "question": "What is the average lifespan of the hummingbird?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8c", "question": "What is the capital of Senegal?", "answer": "Dakar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd957ec223966ae8f88df", "question": "What movie villain was inspired, in part, by Katharine Hepburn?", "answer": "Hannibal Lector", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae860f34007905755f79e90", "question": "Who was the first woman in space?", "answer": "Valentina Tereshkova", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81b39d0de9af39e9d4676", "question": "What ancient people created massive head figurines out of boulders?", "answer": "The Olmec", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c78", "question": "Which movie introduced Indiana Jones to the public?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e6", "question": "What two states share a border with Florida?", "answer": "Alabama and Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02c", "question": "What does Amoco stand for?", "answer": "American Oil Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a2", "question": "Why is Max mad in the 1979 movie \"Mad Max\"?", "answer": "His wife and child were murdered", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398dd", "question": "The Emmy Awards honor excellence in what industry?", "answer": "Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57e", "question": "What is the capital of County Kerry, Ireland?", "answer": "Tralee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339632", "question": "In the 1995 movie \"Babe\", what Christmas carol does Babe sing?", "answer": "Jingle Bells", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5e9a6ce05a3942286e37", "question": "Which Christmas carol did Bruce Springsteen record live and then release?", "answer": "Santa Claus Is Coming to Town", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cc45bb53d1af658864df", "question": "How many years after the founding of the company did Hallmark release its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590498b2cf93664eb104868a", "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac4", "question": "What \"C\" word is the name for a two-hulled boat?", "answer": "Catamaran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febba037e83c707845b2142", "question": "What is the object that opposing players must destroy in order to win at \"League of Legends\"?", "answer": "Nexus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b296", "question": "Washington's famous crossing of the Delaware was en route to what Revolutionary War battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e4", "question": "Who was born as Frederick Austerlitz?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf88", "question": "How many pieces are found in a standard chess set?", "answer": "32", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c96", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Norwich, Vermont?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1ef80145fb2946670738d", "question": "What nut is hidden in Christmas rice pudding in Sweden?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81b4fd0de9af39e9d4677", "question": "What president gave the longest inaugural speech?", "answer": "William Henry Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a404", "question": "Thursday Island is located in the Torres Strait off the coast of what country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6018bc9ed96d05b23b281659", "question": "Ken Thompson and Dennis Ritchie co-created which operating system?", "answer": "Unix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c4", "question": "What commonly used drug is also used as a natural pesticide?", "answer": "Caffeine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3d3544f0f6af5b066638", "question": "What is the color of the Italian liqeuer Galliano?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b8", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Maurice \"Rocket\" Richard born?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338885", "question": "What does a bibliophile enjoy?", "answer": "Books", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d9", "question": "What was the capital city of West Germany from 1949 to 1990?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c405", "question": "The loose skin hanging from the neck of a chicken is known as a what?", "answer": "Wattle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67e", "question": "What type of chemical bonding occurs between hydrogen and chlorine?", "answer": "Covalent", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b4c701dd7bf43be5e7c7", "question": "How old do you have to be to serve in the U.S. Senate?", "answer": "30 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdabd760b8cce1e6fda7063", "question": "What meat is the primary ingredient in Booyah, a thick stew?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b981", "question": "What used to be called the apple of love or love apple ?", "answer": "The tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ffb133a3a814d89068c61", "question": "The US made \"Medium Tank, M4\" is better known as what?", "answer": "The Sherman tank", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40f", "question": "The first consumer products made from plastics were what?", "answer": "Hair combs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0df12fcbed638185eaa18", "question": "What is the largest ski area in the world?", "answer": "Les Trois Vall\u00e9es, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb675c5dad637d903c883d", "question": "According to its former minister of tourism, which country is known abroad for its three Rs: reggae, romance and running?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339243", "question": "What is the main character's job in the movie \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Archeologist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87c", "question": "What chemical element has an extra syllable in its more correct British pronunciation?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c411", "question": "What element has the atomic number 26?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe937cb6bd93ce3a4e5f677", "question": "Genuphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Knees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339803", "question": "What movie did rappers Ice Cube & Ice T star in?", "answer": "Tresspass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c9", "question": "What is the term for a wolf's home?", "answer": "Den", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b291", "question": "What Canadian territory came into existence on April 1, 1999?", "answer": "Nunavut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c98f877e98cb977789f6", "question": "In which city was the oldest university in Scandinavia founded in 1477?", "answer": "Uppsala", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddb826ce05a3942286d90", "question": "In 1997 movie, \"Titanic\", what was the name of Rose's maid?", "answer": "Trudy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e6", "question": "Who plays the role of Mick \"Crocodile\" Dundee in the movie \"Crocodile Dundee\"?", "answer": "Paul Hogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7be", "question": "What is measured in Becquerels?", "answer": "Radioactivity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b7", "question": "A famous misquote of Voltaire describes Canada as simply \"a few acres of\" what?", "answer": "Snow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c939fbde8045e48466e9", "question": "Which farm animal has the largest eyes of any land mammal?", "answer": "Horses -- They perceive objects 50% larger than human eyes do. Horses also have monocular vision -- they see things with one eye.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339239", "question": "Who performed \"Bitter Sweet Symphony\" with Coldplay at the Live 8 concert?", "answer": "Richard Ashcroft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d9e6709c1c34536e6ead", "question": "The fans of Taylor Swift are known as what?", "answer": "Swifties", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae84", "question": "In 1915, what steamship was torpedoed by a German submarine, killing over 1000 passengers?", "answer": "Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b7", "question": "When did boxer John L. Sullivan die?", "answer": "1918", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac24", "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the south?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d5412b42d4a3561a9f00", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of Francine\u2019s daughter?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3c2894f032c0db195b482", "question": "When Santa Anna had his leg amputated after engaging the French at Veracruz, what did he do with it?", "answer": "He ordered a full military burial for the lost limb.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbd", "question": "What state saw the start of the American Revolution?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ca", "question": "Who sang the song \"Foolish Games\"?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339066", "question": "What does the Latin word \"Verbatim\" literally means?", "answer": "Word for word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9f", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Buchanan?", "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c259", "question": "What is another name for tetanus?", "answer": "Lockjaw", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db2", "question": "In the show \"Jackie Chan Adventures\", which antagonist turned into a protagonist after the show's first season?", "answer": "Tohru", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e1", "question": "What is a judo practitioner's Judogi?", "answer": "Uniform", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b92", "question": "What wealthy comic-book title character keeps his mansion tidy with the help of a robot maid, Irona?", "answer": "Richie Rich", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e95527ccba3ffe45786de", "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6f", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Autobiography of a Horse\"?", "answer": "Black Beauty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b3711b1c3f17ccc40c8e1c", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a591", "question": "Which US state is called the Magnolia State?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7eba2b24f84e0b9f9ffdf", "question": "What town's name means \"House of Bread\" in Hebrew?", "answer": "Bethlehem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c922", "question": "John Augustus Larson invented what in 1921?", "answer": "Lie detector (Polygraph)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fc", "question": "Who was the King of Swing?", "answer": "Benny Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fad", "question": "What movie's title mission is completed using the Five-Point-Palm Exploding Heart Technique?", "answer": "Kill Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b031", "question": "Who was the last US president of the 19th century?", "answer": "William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefd", "question": "What did explorer Robert Peary attempt to reach in 1909?", "answer": "The North Pole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab0b36baab681b09292166", "question": "Who was the first king of Jerusalem?", "answer": "King Saul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b32001dd7bf43be5e7a8", "question": "Where did the corgi dog breed get its name?", "answer": "Welsh for \"dwarf\" dog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936e", "question": "Which actor appears in both the 1968 and 1999 versions of the movie \"The Thomas Crown Affair\"?", "answer": "Faye Dunaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909ccedbb53d1af658864e5", "question": "What branch of Christianity introduced the Advent calendar?", "answer": "German Lutherans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8dd", "question": "The Yellow River is what country's second longest?", "answer": "China's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f5", "question": "What was the name of Ross' monkey in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Marcel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b372481c3f17ccc40c8e22", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b2", "question": "Who played the role of officer Williams in the TV series \"In The Heat of the Night\"?", "answer": "David Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fa", "question": "Somnoplasty is a cosmetic procedure designed to help with what?", "answer": "Snoring", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e0", "question": "Which British sax player fronted the band \"Paraphernalia\"?", "answer": "Barbara Thompson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e922b24f84e0b9f9ffca", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e9b606d333868d34d758", "question": "What were \"Jungle Fountains\" during World War II?", "answer": "Coca-Cola provided to the U.S. troops.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b372061c3f17ccc40c8e21", "question": "The detective novel \"The Body in the library\" was written by which novelist?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20f", "question": "Jason Voorhees first appeared in the nightmare of which \"Friday the 13th\" character?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb82", "question": "Canfield, Klondike, and Pyramid are variations of what card game?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa56e2c73aa70ea0b70b2e", "question": "In Portugal, what object is traditionally thrown at friends in celebration of April Fool's Day?", "answer": "Flour (Flour bombing' is an established April Fool's Day practice in Portugal and some other countries.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b5749076251badbeac3", "question": "For what does NAACP stand?", "answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fe", "question": "In the SNL Digital Short \"Lazy Sunday\", what movie were the characters going to see?", "answer": "The Chronicles of Narnia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76b93eec85e375820b2c4", "question": "Where can you hike Hadrian\u2019s wall?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b96", "question": "What actor built a working full\u00adsize painter's studio for himself in preparation for his role as a famous artist?", "answer": "Ed Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3796ff048f679a45ab1a", "question": "In which country was the largest known T-Rex skeleton found?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedd9e96ce05a3942286d7e", "question": "What was the name of the girl in the film \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Lex Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3df", "question": "What was the first vitamin to be discovered and named?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8922ec223966ae8f8826", "question": "Who is the artist who sings \"Beauty School Dropout\" in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "Frankie Avalon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c6c4877e98cb977789bf", "question": "What country has a national park called the \"Valley of Flowers\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c945", "question": "Kr is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Krypton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339791", "question": "What KISS star sported the longest tongue in rock?", "answer": "Gene Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40c", "question": "What is the capital of Australia?", "answer": "Canberra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b06be662d71a53650fc8", "question": "The four routes through the Vatican Museums all end at what showstopper?", "answer": "Michelangelo\u2019s Creation of Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ce", "question": "Which is the largest of the Caribbean islands?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7abb2c6490a8cc1a6e5294", "question": "In computer programming, which logic gate outputs TRUE if both inputs are TRUE?", "answer": "AND", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c62b8540ae4aacefc17eee0", "question": "Who are the Pines twins in the TV show \"Gravity Falls\"?", "answer": "Dipper and Mabel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339839", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"52nd Street\"?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e870fe83fe1f2a824bdd", "question": "Which 19th-century Englishwoman became the first qualified medical doctor?", "answer": "Elizabeth Garrett Anderson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e55", "question": "Who had the last number one hit of the 1950s with his song \"Why\"?", "answer": "Frankie Avalon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d070d1a1c922dd1ac64b4", "question": "Which town do Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty live in?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339093", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hades?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hera, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa6e873838c5c8a417f33", "question": "Which is the most dangerous tree in the world?", "answer": "Manchineel tree (Found in the Florida Everglades and coastal Caribbean, its sap will cause blisters with the slightest contact.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce5", "question": "What is Mr. Belvedere's given name?", "answer": "Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73503eec85e375820b241", "question": "On two separate occasions, President Ford was shot at by which two people?", "answer": "Lynette \"Squeaky\" Fromme and Sara Jane Moore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab59", "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe river flow?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9056d01dd7bf43be5e87b", "question": "What does \"In pace requiescat\" translate into?", "answer": "Rest in peace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76f37eec85e375820b2e4", "question": "Where was Mozart born?", "answer": "Salzburg, Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c256", "question": "What is the SI physical unit of dynamic viscosity?", "answer": "Pascal-second", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a533", "question": "The Missouri River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f48", "question": "What woman's name has one \"L\" according to Elvis Costello but two according to the Pixies?", "answer": "Allison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c7", "question": "The resort city of Aspen is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592201b0a4edfd43a087addb", "question": "What is the first name of the fictional character \"Miss Marple\"?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3c2b24f032c0db195b484", "question": "Which dictator composed six operas?", "answer": "Kim Jong-il was the supreme leader of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa41", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Canberra?", "answer": "Australian Capital Territory", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b06", "question": "On \"Saturday Night Live\", what Weekend Update anchor signed off with the line, \"and that's news to me\"?", "answer": "Kevin Nealon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7389beec85e375820b265", "question": "What currency is used in South Africa?", "answer": "Rand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53c", "question": "What word in the English language with three consecutive sets of double letters?", "answer": "Bookkeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad35", "question": "Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. received his Ph.D. from which school?", "answer": "Boston University", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0a", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal pitched by Snap, Crackle and Pop?", "answer": "Rice Krispies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a047", "question": "What song was Hawaiin Don Ho most known for?", "answer": "Tiny Bubbles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb357d02627b8fe95581be5", "question": "Within the English language, what author has the most published books?", "answer": "L. Ron Hubbard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc3126de0eb824d4052ea", "question": "What is the oldest bridge across Venice's Grand Canal?", "answer": "Rialto Bridge -- Built by architect-engineer Antonio da Ponte and his nephew, the bridge is supported by 6,000 timber piles.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca10", "question": "Pediculophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Lice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb08a71cf631c2414a13b60", "question": "What is singer Fergie\u2019s real name?", "answer": "Stacy Ann Ferguson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6fc", "question": "The city of Baton Rouge is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c4", "question": "The word gherkin, a small pickle, is based on the Dutch word \"gurken\" meaning what?", "answer": "Cucumbers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fcc1b64c97eb73f6a51a271", "question": "Who said, \"Love the life you live. Live the life you love\"?", "answer": "Bob Marley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e73", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Sneakers\"?", "answer": "David Strathairn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaed2f0738315b1fb74e2f", "question": "In what year did the first president of Kenya, Jomo Kenyatta, die?", "answer": "1978", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9f", "question": "In Greek mythology Cronus and Rhea were the parents of who?", "answer": "Zeus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f0d26682715b82711cda", "question": "What does the saying \"Requiescat in pace\" abbreviate to?", "answer": "RIP", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d4700bf8e329de4f87788d", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the saxophone?", "answer": "Adolphe Sax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173fcf44491cbd7c5a17b6", "question": "What is the name of the pagan festival that used to be held during the same period as Valentine's Day?", "answer": "Lupercalia was a festival dedicated to Faunus, the Roman god of agriculture. It was held the middle of February.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbe1f6ce05a3942286ee8", "question": "The film \"The African Queen\" is set during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bba0fb6c85e9e634ff57", "question": "Managua is the capital of which Central American country?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ee1606d333868d34d773", "question": "Easter comes after how many days of Lent in the Christian calendar?", "answer": "40 days", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000ed819a72b906b34e3ced", "question": "Who discovered the mathematical system of logarithms?", "answer": "John Napier", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e4", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Georgia?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cf", "question": "How did Alice enter Wonderland?", "answer": "Through a Rabbit Hole", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b657", "question": "What company introduced the first radio with push-button tuning in 1927?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3e1e44f0f6af5b066645", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 15?", "answer": "Femto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde49fec6c6b019850c9a71", "question": "Which two nations fought for control of North America in the French and Indian War?", "answer": "France and England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf59", "question": "Who wrote the mIRC chat software?", "answer": "Khaled Mardam-Bey", "category": "general"}]